The year the country split apart and a generation came together.
1969 is a drama, war, romance film directed by Ernest Thompson.
Two rebellious youths, Ralph and Scott, find themselves
struggling with adulthood as the Vietnam War rages.
Feeling trapped in their small town, Scott battles with his conservative veteran
father, Cliff, and Ralph deals with his desperately sexual mother, Ev.
When tragic news arrives from overseas, the entire town, inspired by Ralph and
Scott's antiwar efforts, reevaluates its attitude toward the war.
Ralph Carr, played by Robert Downey Jr..
Scott Clifton Denny, played by Kiefer Sutherland.
Cliff Denny, played by Bruce Dern.
Jessie Denny, played by Mariette Hartley.
Beth Carr, played by Winona Ryder.
Ev Carr, played by Joanna Cassidy.
1969 is a 1988 American drama film written and directed by Ernest Thompson and
starring Robert Downey Jr., Kiefer Sutherland and Winona Ryder.
The original music score is composed by Michael Small.
The film deals with the Vietnam War and the resulting social tensions between
those who support and oppose the war in small-town America.
The film explores themes of small town, vietnam, graduation, 1960s.
The tone is emotional.